David Souza

Web Developer/DNS Engineer at Apple

Summary

Over 15 years of experience as a professional web developer committed to building successful apps that are easy to use, deliver value to customers, and are easy to maintain.

Developer of large scale web applications using PHP, Ruby on Rails, MySQL, CodeIgniter, Laravel, HTML 5, CSS 3, and JavaScript.

Built multiple iOS Applications using PhoneGap/Cordova and jQuery Mobile. Currently building iOS applications using Core Bluetooth and Swift.

Well versed in many software development methodologies including Agile Software Development and the complete Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) process which includes Designing, Developing, Testing, Implementation and Deployment.

Experience

Web Developer/DNS Engineer at Apple

September 2015 - Present

- Help to manage DNS @ Apple both internal and external
- Created and built internal web applications/tools for managing and maintaining DNS, using Go, PHP, MySQL, Perl, JavaScript, & Shell scripting

Web Development Engineer at Apple

August 2011 - September 2015 (4 years 1 month)

- Build and maintain large scale internal web applications to handle both assets and deliverables across many departments
- Performance testing/improvements for both client side and database driven applications to create a better user experience
- Created and built internal web applications for project & process management, using Ruby on Rails, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, &

Shell scripting

Build, upgrade, and manage servers and VMs for hosting and deploying web applications

Web Development Manager at Apple

October 2009 - August 2011 (1 year 10 months)

- Managed a software development team that varied from 4 to 8 people for creating internal tools for project
 & process management
- Managed multiple, concurrent software projects in multiple programming languages, including hiring and building the teams
- Helped to move the software development process to a more agile process, while continuing to deliver features and improvements

Web Development Engineer at Apple

August 2000 - October 2009 (9 years 2 months)

- Developed and maintained a number of large scale web applications
- Design and development of a CMS and deployment tool for building out large websites in multiple languages
- Performance testing/improvements for both client side and database driven applications

VP of Manufacturing

June 1990 - July 2000 (10 years 1 month)

- Managed the manufacturing process from design to finished product for 10 15 different hardward/software products
- Managed product design, purchasing, all PCB manufacturing and assembly, product testing/revisions, and packaging design

Education

San Jose State University

Business Finance, 1991 - 1994

De Anza College

AA, Accounting, 1988 - 1991

David Souza

Web Developer/DNS Engineer at Apple



Contact David on LinkedIn